THOMAS MATLOCK, CISA

Systems Manager / Full Stack Developer

- **♀** Jackson, Mississippi
- **(**601) 812-8079
- ☑ thomasmatlockbba@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/twmatlock
- github.com/zep1994

Education -

- Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA), ISACA
- Basic Linux, Cloud Academy
- Onbase, Hyland
- Full Stack Software Development Bootcamp Program, Flatiron School, New York City, New York
- Bachelor of Science in Business
 Administration, University of Mississippi
- Responsive Web Development, freeCodeCamp
- JavaScript: Classes, LinkedIn Learning

Technical ·

JavaScript, Node, SQL / NoSQL, Ruby / Python, Unix / Linux / Git / Bash, Web, HTML / HTML5 / CSS / React / NextJS, Strapi / CMS, Apache / Nginx, ES6, React Frameworks, AWS, Redux.js, OpenCV, VueJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Laravel, MySQL, PHP, API Development, Bootstrap, MongoDB, jQuery, AJAX, REST APIs, OOP, SQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Ruby on Rails, ACL, Mobile Application Development, Data-Mining / Data Manipulation / Data Modeling, Windows Task Scheduler, Google Suite, Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office / Teams / Zoom / WebEx / GoToMeeting, Social Media: Facebook, Pinterest, LinkedIn, Twitter, and Instagram.

Skills

- Data Analytics / Data Mining
- Back-End Web Development / Front-End Development
- Data Strategy / Data Governance
- IT System Integration
- Infrastructure Migration
- Project / Program / Product Management
- Agile Methodologies
- Cross-Functional Team Leadership
- Disaster Recovery / Enterprise Security

Executive Summary

A rising full-stack agile developer, systems manager, and pragmatic bridge-builder who is piloting business-centric roadmaps, empowering independence, and inspiring the next generation of enterprise growth in multi-million dollar organizations.

Experienced strategist for software development, data analytics, scripting, project management, back-end web development, front-end development, solution architecture, enterprise risk management, compliance, reporting solutions, business intelligence, operations, integration, SDLC, and enterprise transformation.

A transformer who serves as a catalyst for sustainable change by empowering organizations and people to achieve breakthrough results as they travel to digital transformations. Applies extraordinary acumen in pushing the boundaries of what's possible.

Full Stack Developer Innovator/ Enterprise Applications Thought Leader

Transformational Leader / Systems Manager

Digital & Strategic Collaborator / Agile Change Agent

Java / CSS / HTML / Node.js / Python / SQL / JavaScript / Git / MongoDB

Team Mentor / Trusted IT Business Partner

'An exceptional Full Stack Development Strategist and Systems Manager, with passion, and the drive for perfection...'

'Thomas is a highly skilled full-stack developer and systems management innovator who operates at a very high level. He constantly seeks opportunities that add tremendous value to new projects and facilitates intellectual curiosity. Thomas has the unique ability to communicate effectively with all levels of the organization and achieve collective consensus. He is a culture builder who provides expertise and best practices and is adept at leveraging his influence without authority by developing and cultivating key relationships. It is his combination of technical acumen, intellect, drive, leadership, and flexibility that enables him to excel. He is highly intelligent, has a remarkable work ethic, and has deep intellectual knowledge.'

- Excerpt from a recent performance appraisal.

Professional History

2022 - 2023 Systems Manager / Full Stack Developer

Liquid Creative

- Spearheaded systems management; developed, implemented, and oversaw organizational backup/storage processes to safeguard data loss and optimize system performance levels.
- Cut annual costs by \$20,000+ dollars through the acquisition and implementation of new software.
- Coordinated and controlled the hosting of 50+ websites utilizing a full stack of web technologies, such as NextJS, Laravel, and Postgres.
- Owned the total commercial client relationship from onboarding implementation, training, account management, enterprise and concierge, client ticketing triage, and client call support, striving for high levels of client satisfaction measured through system adoption, retention, and client feedback loops.
- Designed, delivered, and optimized two incremental sites in less than 30 days to dramatically improve departmental wait times.
- Authored and conceptualized a key efficiency project which cut costs by 10+ hours weekly and dramatically improved SDLC.

2022 - 2022 Systems Auditor

CSpire

 Orchestrated leadership as systems auditor; risk analysis/mitigation, data analytics, systems analysis/vulnerabilities, compliance, solutions architecture, and testing.

Skills

- Strategic Technology Planning, Forecasting & Analysis
- Process Engineering / Automation
- Risk / Change Management
- Vendor Management
- Strategic Enterprise Transformation
- Training / Mentorship / Leadership
- Communication / Collaboration
- Continual Process Improvement
- Time Management / Multitasking
- Thought Leadership
- Strategic Mutually Beneficial Relationships
- Enterprise Governance / Compliance
- Collaborative Vision & Goal Setting
- Communication / Collaboration / Conflict Resolution
- Continual Process Improvement
- Operational Excellence
- Execution / Results
- Turning Data Insight to Real Impact
- Predictive Data Analytics
- Emotional Intelligence / EQ
- Pragmatic / Creativity / Problem Solving
- Influence / Resilience / Integrity
- Flexibility / Adaptability / Persuasion
- Business Intelligence / Data Visualization
- Agile Innovation / Development
- Leveraging Analytics
- Digital Transformation
- Diversity / Inclusion
- Strategic Enterprise Transformation / Planning

- Fueled cost savings of \$50,000+ dollars through extensive data mining/analytics of millions of records.
- Utilized Windows Task Scheduler, Python, and ACL in conjunction with SQL queries.
- Secured massive cost savings by implementing ACL and Python in the continuous monitoring for Agile Auditing.
- Cross-functionally collaborated with developers in analyzing and resolving critical
 opportunities with databases, performance, and other issues; documented testing
 processes.

2021 - 2022 IT Internal Auditor

Ergon, Inc.

- Championed organizational leadership as an internal auditor; cross-functionally liaised with internal and external leaders and stakeholders in system compliance, vulnerabilities, and optimization.
- Delivered \$100,000+ dollars in yearly savings through critical risk monitoring and analysis.
- Built and implemented automated workflows that ran 32+ scripts, analyzing millions of records, and pinpointing anomalies within the system.
- Succeeded in capturing 3+ cases of fraud and created and implemented new innovative control systems as a result.
- Engineered, established, and maintained innovative audit software for millions of journal entries and developed vital system theft controls based on risk analytics; delivered key reports to stakeholders.

2020 - 2021 System Administrator / Software Developer

Ergon, Inc

- Pioneered software application and system administrator development leadership; data migrations, system migrations; designed and implemented systems and re-platforming applications, database design, data structures, and web applications.
- Succeeded in eliminating manual labor hours through the development and implementation of a Python script that created an automated workflow based on customer needs

2019 - 2020 Software Developer

Mthree

- Delivered \$750,000 in incremental yearly revenue through the development of critical strategies that increased daily customer volume by 25%.
- Cut research time by 50% through the development of an application that dramatically improved daily workflows.
- Utilized Linux systems and applied Regex to search for inconsistencies and recognize errors.
- Designed and established a CLI program that saved each team member 160+ hours yearly.
- Cut query time to seconds through the utilization of SQL to query the database and improve productivity.
- $\bullet \quad \hbox{Established TCP/IP connections emphasizing the application and network layer.}$